Katherine Garrison Chapin Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
Katherine Garrison Chapin Papers 1930-1972
MSS12682
Chapin, Katherine Garrison, 1890-1977
1,200 items
7 containers
2.8 linear feet
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress Washington, D.C.
Poet and author. Correspondence, writings, and other material relating mainly to Garrison's published and unpublished poetry and plays.
Selected Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the LC Catalog. They are grouped by name of person or organization, by subject or location, and by occupation and listed alphabetically.
People
Chapin, Katherine Garrison, 1890-1977.
Subjects
American literature.; American poetry.; Literature.; Poetry.
Occupations
Authors.; Poets.
Provenance
The papers of Katherine Garrison Chapin, poet and author, were given to the Library of Congress at her bequest in 1979.
Transfers
Musical scores were transferred to the Library's Music Division where they are identified as part of these papers.
Access and Restrictions
Restrictions apply governing the use, photoduplication, or publication of items in this collection. Consult reference staff in the Manuscript Division for information concerning these restrictions. In addition, many collections are stored off-site and advance notice is needed to retrieve these items for research use.
Biographical Note
Katherine Garrison Chapin was born in Waterford, Connecticut, on September 4, 1890, and died in Pennsylvania on December 30, 1977. She was educated at Columbia University and beginning in the 1920s became published as a poet in such publications as Harper's, Scribner's, Saturday Review, North American Review, Poetry, and the Ladies' Home Journal. Other of her works were set to music and performed by leading orchestras. In 1918 she married Francis Biddle, later attorney general in the administration of Franklin D. Roosevelt during World War II.
Scope and Content Note
The papers of Katherine Garrison Chapin (1890-1977) span the years 1930-1972. The collection consists of correspondence; drafts of plays, poems, short stories, articles, and other writings; notes and notebooks; reviews; biographical material; publicity material; and printed matter. The bulk of the papers consists of drafts of published and unpublished poetry and plays, including "Sojourner Truth," "The Tapestry of the Duchess," "The Other Journey," and "To Speak Before Sleep." The collection is arranged by type of material.
Arrangement of the Papers
This collection is arranged by type of material.
Container List
- Poems (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous poems, published and unpublished, (5 folders) (Box 1)
  - "The Other Journey," 1954, 1959, (2 folders) (Box 1)
  - "To Speak Before Sleep," 1964 (Box 1)
  - "Up From the Waters, a Negro Dance Poem" (Box 1)
  - Botteghe Oscure, notes and plans for anthology, 1964-1968 (Box 2)
  - Time Has No Shadow, publicity, 1936 (Box 2)
  - Outside of the World, publicity, 1930 (Box 2)
- Short stories (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous short stories, (2 folders) (Box 2)
  - "Notes for a Brahms Symphony" (Box 2)
- Plays (Box 2)
  - One act (Box 2)
  - "The Tapestry of the Duchess", (2 folders) (Box 3)
  - "The Lady of the Inn," 1942 (Box 3)
  - "Summer Holiday," 1952 (Box 3)
  - "Ladies of Bayeux", (2 folders) (Box 3)
  - "Sojourner Truth" (Box 3)
    - Copyright deposits, 1944, 1947, (2 folders) (Box 3)
    - Drafts, (3 folders) (Box 3)
    - Notebooks, (9 vols.) (Box 4)
    - Rough draft, 1931 (Box 4)
- Lyrics (Box 4)
  - "And They Lynched Him on a Tree," program, 1940, June 24 (Box 4)
  - Lament for the Stolen (Box 4)
    - Correspondence and other material (Box 4)
    - Publicity and biographical sketch (Box 4)
    - Orchestra publicity (Box 4)
    - Pamphlets (Box 4)
    - Clippings (Box 4)
    - WFIL radio, Philadelphia, Pa., talk (Box 4)
- Ballets, (2 folders) (Box 5)
- Choric Players (Box 5)
- World War II items (Box 5)
- Radio (Box 5)
  - Broadcast notes (Box 5)
  - Radio talks, rough copies, (4 folders) (Box 5)
  - WOR, New York, N.Y., 1938, Mar. (Box 5)
  - Miscellaneous speeches, 1937, Apr.-May (Box 5)
- Articles, notes, and speeches (Box 5)
  - Miscellaneous notes (Box 5)
  - St. John Perse, (1 folder); (7 folders) (Box 5, Box 6)
  - New Bedford, Mass., article, 1961, Sept. (Box 6)
  - Miscellaneous speech notes, (2 folders) (Box 6)
  - "Frost Letters" notes, 1964, Nov.-Dec. (Box 6)
  - New Republic, 1971 (Box 6)
  - Berenson, Bernard, article (Box 6)
  - Book reviews, (2 folders) (Box 7)
  - University of Texas, Austin, Tex., 1960-1961 (Box 7)
  - Library of Congress, 1953, Dec. 14 (Box 7)
  - Literary Society, 1970, Dec. 5 (Box 7)
  - Miscellaneous articles and speeches on poetry (Box 7)
  - Speech note cards (Box 7)